# **Prerana Chakraborty**

0035677666783 / PRERANACHAKRABORTY17@gmail.com / LinkedIn / GitHub

# Summary

I am working at KPMG Microsoft Business Solutions Malta as a Junior Data Engineer in the Data Analytics team in Intelligent Cloud Practice since October 2023. I have around 2 years of experience with Azure Synapse (PySpark) and Power BI currently working on end-to-end Data Engineering and BI solutions. Currently I am working on a UK based professional accounting company client on D365 to Azure data platform integration and transformation journey. Previously I have worked at Wipro Limited in India as Associate (Data Analytics) for more than 1 year and I have advanced knowledge of Power BI, Azure Data Platform (ADF, Synapse, PySpark), Excel, DAX and SQL.

## Technical Skills

**Languages**: Python (PySpark), SQL (Spark SQL and SQL Server) **Developer Tools**: GitHub, Azure DevOps, Cloud Platform, PyCharm

Clouds: Azure (Azure Synapse, Azure Data Factory, Azure Data Lake Gen2), Databricks

Reporting Tools: Power BI, Fabric, Excel

Business Tools: Excel, Power Point, SharePoint, D365 F&O

# Experience

## **Junior Analyst Programmer (Data Engineer)**

Oct 2023 – Current

KPMG Microsoft Business Solutions (Malta) Ltd.

Marsa, Malta

- Developed and maintained PySpark notebooks, Spark SQL scripts, and Azure ELT pipelines to streamline data load processes and enhance data reporting efficiency, contributing to BI system performance optimization.
- Designed and implemented scalable Azure cloud data platform infrastructures (used Synapse, ADLS, ADF, Azure SQL DB), cutting cloud costs by 35% while ensuring robust security and performance for one of largest Professional Accountancy Certification Client based out of UK.
- Built Data ingestion pipeline from Web API to Lakehouse using Microsoft Fabric using PySpark Notebooks
- Power BI Report Design and Development and Deployment for L&D team for Training Calendar Preparation, reduced overall analytics insights generation efforts by 80%
- Member of ESG and Social Committee and organized Clean-ups and hikes

### Associate (Power BI Developer)

May 2021 – Aug 2022

Wipro Ltd

Bangalore, India

- Developed Power BI (SSRS) Reports for Employee Performance Analysis for 1000+ member practice
- Involved in Requirement Analysis, HR KPI Creation, Power BI DAX Measures development
- HR Data Analysis in SQL and Normalized Data Model Creation
- Data Cleansing, Report performance optimization, Role Based Access Control

#### Certifications

DP-203: Data Engineer Associate	Microsoft
DP-500: Azure Enterprise Data Analyst Associate	Microsoft
DP-600: Fabric Analytics Engineer Associate	Microsoft
PL-300: Power BI Data Analyst Associate	Microsoft
AZ-900: Azure Fundamentals	Microsoft
DP-900: Azure Data Fundamentals	Microsoft
Consulting 101	KPMG

### Education

## Visva Bharati University

Santiniketan, West Bengal, India

Bachelors in Geography Masters in Geography Bachelors in Education Aug. 2013 – Jun 2016 Jul. 2016 – Jun 2018 Aug. 2018 – Sep 2020